Hi guys, down in the dumpster room.
Sorry about the crap crap quality.
Shooting this on the phone. Didn't have
time to go get my
good camera. So, audio and video is
probably going to suck, BUT CHECK OUT
WHAT I FOUND IN THE DUMPSTER.
UNBELIEVABLE. HANG ON.
Let's see if we still got it. It looks
like
a some sort of Keysight, one of these
huge series scopes. I'm not sure how old
it is. One of those big heavy beasts.
I've never found a scope in the UH
DUMPSTER BEFORE. ALTHOUGH, I AM AWARE
that there are a couple of
you know high-tech companies that would
use such a high-end
scope in the business park, BUT
I WHAT A SCORE. I DON'T KNOW WHAT model
number it is. We'll check it out. I'll
get this sucker out and we'll take it
back to the lab and
check it out.
Hopefully, it's a winner winner chicken
dinner, but
it's in the dumpster for a reason.
Let's go. This could be awesome.
Holy
oscilloscopes, Batman. This has got to
be the dumpster score of the decade.
This is You're not going to believe Look
at me. Agilent, not this Keysight
rubbish. Infiniium DSOX93200
series, but it's the like the top of the
line unit, the 32 gig bandwidth, 80 gig
samples per second.
Wha I
Yeah. Why would you throw this out? I
can only imagine that because this is
not your average everyday use
oscilloscope. Like maximum like 50 ohm
inputs only, maximum plus minus 5 volts.
You know, you get idiots going around
you know just plugging in and thinking
they can use this as a regular scope and
just blow the front end. So, it wouldn't
surprise me if that's what's happened.
Blow in the front end and
too expensive to fix the thing, but this
thing is worth a
fortune.
If it work if it works. Hmm. And it's
not in bad nick either. Obviously came
out of some lab. I have no idea what
that means.
And
it looks like they got the contact on
there Ed. Good on you Ed. Looks in great
nick on the back too. It's got the hard
drive as removable here. GPIB interface
as you'd expect. PCI Express times four.
Expansion DVI output for an external
monitor. And curiously though it's only
25 gig on here.
So I guess maybe that's what the option
801 there does. I don't know. I haven't
checked. Now unfortunately this doesn't
use regular BNCs. As I said this is you
know BNCs it might be able to get those
on like you know up to 10 gig scopes or
something whatever sort of the maximum.
You can get BNCs that go a bit higher I
think but basically on this high
bandwidth ones you get these custom
jobbies. They all look or they feel all
loosey-goosey but they're designed to be
that. Looks like they're an SMA but a
male one. It's got a Cal output and
that's got a similar
thing. So yeah I might be able to cobble
something together to get a signal in.
All right, fingers crossed. Here we go.
Yeah.
Hold it down.
Nope.
Not a sausage. Unfortunately we're
getting nothing on there and it doesn't
have like a separate power switch on the
back. So the the primary is open. Let's
Looks like we're going to have to crack
it open. Actually curiously there was no
like Cal sticker on the back of this
preventing you or the bottom preventing
you actually taking this off. This is
not coming off without a fight. Three
screws on the back and ow, ow, ow. Bit
of bloody aluminum in there. Going to
have to get the tweezers out for that,
but we're are in like Flynn. Awesome.
There's our
main standard PC motherboard. Every
Nothing uh
nothing particularly special at all. So,
it's not like they got a big controller
board in here. It looks like everything
is just um SATA going over and that's
well, you know, SATA is super high-speed
interface. It does the business. So, no
worries whatsoever. There's all your
serious hardware down in there. That's
what you're paying,
you know, $100,000 or whatever for. That
is a, you know, ooh, some serious
serious RF stuff happening down there.
Look at that.
Wow.
Woah, no touchy. And we've got some
serious cooling on here, too. This puppy
is going to be loud. You don't want to
use this for your everyday use lab
scope, even if you could. Now, of
course, what we want to look for is the
power supply, but I actually came over
here. This is the power supply all in
here. It looks like it lists out if you
get these cables out, but this the main
cable here, it's got a
it's got a little, you know, hook catch
thing on it, but that was kind of not
all the way
in. It was sort of sitting out. So, I'm
going to bust it out. That's all right.
And that's all right. And the contact is
a bit it doesn't make proper click. I
expect like a click to go in there, but
let's um
let's see.
Hey, now we're talking. Up.
Now, we're talking.
Yeah, it's all over the place. That's
just the input
stuff on the power supply, but is that
all that was preventing this thing
powering up? A dicky
a on a power connector. Let's find out.
All right, let's try it now.
Hello.
Whir.
Those fans are whirring.
Can't smell anything. Hello. Hello.
Intel Core 2 Duo 3 gig, whatever. Choose
an operating system to start. Oh, what
Oh. Oh, we're in.
STARTING WINDOWS.
WOOHOO.
And bugger, password. Password is
password. Is that you, Lance?
Keysight.
Joshua.
Nope.
Woohoo. We are in. We are in. It turns
out it was Agilent with a capital A. I
tried Took me a while. I took I tried
all combinations of, you know, Agilent
one, Keysight one, and all sorts of
stuff. It was Agilent with a capital A.
So, we are booting and it's got to
initialize all the Keysight
software, but
we should be able to get in. Wow, that
actually took a while to boot, but we
are in to the main control screen and
you're not going to believe it. It
passes all the internal self-test,
vertical, time base, ADC, acquisition
memory, which is 2 gig, by the way. This
uh all the models in the series I
checked have 2 gig of sample memory at
80 gig samples a second. By the way, the
bandwidth uh 32 uh gig halves to gosh
darn it, only 16 gig when you turn on
all four uh channels. Miss scope group,
whatever that is.
Passes the self-test. What I'm doing, I
found um some female uh
you know, gender changer things for the
SMA, so I am able to actually uh connect
up to this thing. So, I've got the
calibration output actually connected on
here and uh I'm actually generating a
for the calibration output. Ah, no, I
was it reset. There we go.
100 MHz, bingo! Bingo! So, we can
How do we do that? There we go. There we
go. Unbelievable. This thing actually
works. Channel 1 seems to work just
fine. I actually just did the
quick jitter
analysis option here and there we're
analyzing now. Oh, fancy pantsy. This
thing is working like a bought one. I
won't go through I've gone through a
similar scope before with a similar sort
of interface. The interface is horrible.
You would never ever want to use this
for anything but specialized purposes.
But anyway, we can go in there put up to
260 meg. Oh, look at that 536
meg points.
Wow. It's not every day you get to see
two picoseconds per division.
Incredible. And that is an absolutely
perfect 1 gig sine wave. Channel 1 works
just perfectly. I'll try the others. I
forgot that this puppy does actually
have just the auto scale button. I'm not
around. This scope is just
horrible. Yay! Channel 2! Channel 3!
Channel 4!
Winner, winner, chicken dinner!
I have what looks like a fully working
four channel 32 gig 80 gig sample per
second two gig sample memory Infinitum
scope. This is ridiculous. So, I can
only presume that somebody
tossed this out because that the only
thing I could find wrong with it was
that power that dicky power connector
which doesn't look like it latches
Uh, properly in there and it might have
worked its way loose or something and
but I power this thing on and it's
working on all four channels. I mean
that's that's beautiful. Look at that. I
mean we can turn off I've got
acquisition I've got averaging mode
turned on there but you know you can do
all sorts of advanced analysis with this
thing. It's absolutely this is
ridiculous. This thing is worth an
absolute fortune and check it out it
actually comes with all of these
applications. I'm not sure if that's
fully loaded but look DDR4 display port
10 gig ethernet
like maybe
PCI Express. These things I checked the
price of the DDR4 test app there. That
is about 4,000 4 and 1/2 thousand
dollars just for that software option.
Now I made a call to check like a rough
price on this. This is a discontinued
unit the A series I'm not sure what the
latest one is but it's listed as
discontinued on Agilent's website but it
was like state of the art not that many
years ago. It's still a ridiculously
powerful platform. I've been informed
that with the software options on this
thing it's about 300,000
dollars worth if you bought it brand
new. Of course you know you couldn't
sell it for anywhere close to that. In
fact I
wouldn't even know where to sell this.
If you got any ideas where I what I can
possibly do with this thing
it it is the find of the decade. I might
as well give up bloody dumpster diving.
There's no point. It cannot be beat. I
I can't fold it so far but maybe there's
some little subtle thing but if you've
got an idea how I can
offload this thing like it have to you
can't just whack it on eBay, right?
You've got to sell it through some
specialist company who's got the
contacts for somebody who needs a bit of
kit like this and then it cost a fortune
just to calibrate this. An absolute
fortune before anyone would bother
touching it, you know? Um well, at any
sort of reasonable, you know, high
price. Companies are just nuts. Like
they're just like nuts. But that's
chicken feed to a lot of companies that,
you know, it it's nothing. It's served
its purpose and I don't know you know,
it probably sat in the corner gathering
dust and then one day somebody powered
it on and it didn't work and they
they tossed it.
Wow.
Anyway, that is the find of the decade
at least. If you like the video, please
give it a big thumbs up and leave your
comment down below what I can do with
this thing. I can't like
what am I going to do with it? Like, you
know, it's just a doorstop, really. I
mean, it it's ridiculous. If you need
you know,
you need a specialist application. Um
I'll do more extensive testing, but
yeah,
leave your comments down below
what I can do.
Oh.
Nuts.
Catch you next time.